Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Office of the General Secretary-Treasurer records 1957-2009 IBT0018
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Office of the General Secretary-Treasurer records
1957-2009
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
IBT0018
2.5 Linear Feet
This collection contains the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Office of the General Secretary-Treasurer records. Included are rosters dating from 1957-2009.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 2012 [2012.022]
Arrangement
Organized into 2 series: Rosters, and Manuals For Local Union Secretary Treasurers
Biographical / Historical
The General Secretary-Treasurer of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters is the custodian of all properties, funds, securities and assets of the IBT. The GS-T conducts all financial correspondence involving or affecting the union and correspondence regarding financial matters between the IBT and all its affiliates and subordinate bodies. The General Secretary-Treasurer has responsibility for maintaining current information on officers of local unions and joint councils and for issuing such information via annually updated Rosters.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Office of the General Secretary-Treasurer records. Included are rosters dating from 1957-2009, and Manuals dating from 1967-1978.
Conferences; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions; Labor
- Rosters, 1957-2009; Series 1; 1.5 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Arranged Chronologically, Canadian Rosters are located at the end of the series.
  Scope and Contents
  The materials in this series contain the rosters of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters. Included are rosters from local unions, dating 1989-2009 and rosters from the Canadian Conference of Teamsters, dating from 1986-1988. Each roster lists the title, address, and phone number of the local union as well as individual titles, adresses, and phone numbers of the General Executive Board and Trustees.
  Biographical / Historical
  The General-Secretary-Treasurer of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters is responsible for accounting and budget, benefits, information systems, affiliate financial records and other finance-related functions. Production and updating rosters comes under this office's jurisdiction. Rosters provide names and contact information for members of the General Executive Board and Trustees, and officers of local unions, joint councils, state conferences, regional offices, and trade divisions and conferences. IBT rosters are updated and distributed each year in June.
  - Roster, 1957 October 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Roster, 1958 April 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Roster, 1958 October 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Roster, 1959 April 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Roster, 1959 October 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Roster, 1960 October 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Roster, 1961 April 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Roster, 1962 April 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Roster, 1972 April 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Roster, 1982 April 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Roster, 1982 October 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Roster, 1983 April 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Roster, 1983 October 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Roster, 1984 April 1; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Roster, 1984 October 1; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Roster, 1985 April 1; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Roster, 1985 October 1; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Roster, 1986 April 1; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Roster, 1986 October 1; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Roster, 1987 January; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Roster, 1987 April 1; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Roster, 1987 October 1; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Roster, 1988 October 1; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Roster, 1989 April 1; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Roster, 1990 April 1; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Roster, 1990 October 1; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Roster, 1991 April 1; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Roster, 1991 October 1; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Roster, 1993 April 1; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Roster, 2005 July 1; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Roster, 2006 August 1; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Roster, 2009 June 1; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Canadian Roster, 1986 April 15; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Canadian Roster, 1987 May 1; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Canadian Roster, 1988 May 1; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Roster, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Manuals For Local Union Secretary Treasurers, 1962-1978; Series 2; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Arranged chronologically
  The materials in this series contain the manuals of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Local Union Secretary Tresurers. Included are manuals from local unions, dating 1967-1978. Included in each manual are guidelines for financial transactions including: recording cash transaction, reports to governmnet agencies, ect. At the end of each manual is an "exhibits" section which includes pre-printed examples of a working ledger book.
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Recording Monthly Cash Transactions, 1967; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Summaries And Analyses, 1967; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Reports to International, 1967; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Reports to Government Agencies, 1967; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Handling Cash Receipts, 1967; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Exhibits, 1967; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Preface, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Recording Monthly Cash Transactions, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Summaries And Analyses, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Reports To International, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Reports To Government Agencies, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Handling Cash Receipts, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Procedures For Filing, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Local Union 1450 Manual - Exhibits, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - IBT Code Of Accounts - Area Code, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - IBT Code Of Accounts - General Ledger Accounts, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - IBT Code Of Accounts - Sub. Ledger Accounts, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - IBT Code Of Accounts - Investments, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - IBT Code Of Accounts - Individual Code Numbers, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - IBT Code Of Accounts - Financial Report, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - IBT Code Of Accounts - Journal Entries, 1972; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Local Union 1650 Manual - Preface, 1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Local Union 1650 Manual - Contents, 1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Local Union 1650 Manual - Titans, 1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Local Union 1650 Manual - NCR Operations, 1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Local Union 1650 Manual - Manual Operations, 1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Local Union 1650 Manual - Cash Disbursments, 1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Local Union 1650 Manual - Summaries And Analyses, 1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Local Union 1650 Manual - Reports To The International Union, 1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Local Union 1650 Manual - Reports To Government Agencies, 1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Local Union 1650 Manual - Out Of Work Benefits, 1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Local Union 1650 Manual - Exhibits, 1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Retirement and Family Protection Plan, 1975; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Auditors Manual, 1977; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Expense Policies, 2009; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - C. Thomas Kegel Retirement Celebration, 2012; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Ledgers, 1903-1906; 2 Cubic Feet
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  This series contains ledgers from the General Secretary Treasurer from 1903 to 1906. These ledgers outline the daily expenditures of the union during its first few years.
  - "Ledger A" Book, 1903-1904; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Daily Receipts and Expenditures Ledger Book, 1903-1906; Series 3 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Expense Books, 1910-1934
  This series contains expense books from the IBT Office of the General Secretary-Treasurer.
  - Expense Book, 1910-1911; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Expense Book, 1921; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Expense Book, 1928-1934; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Materials, Series 5
  - Passing of C. Thomas Keegel, 20 November 2020; Series 5 (Box Shared Box 36, Folder 12)